# SCOTT DOUGLAS

| H: 602-505-2339 | C: 602-505-2339 | scottdouglas238@gmail.com

Link to my LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/scott-douglas-8482641ab

Link to my GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/scottdouglas238">https://github.com/scottdouglas238</a>

Link to my Portfolio: https://scottdouglas238.github.io/Homework-Portfolio-/

#### **Summary**

Detail oriented individual with effective communication skills geared towards de-escalating situations in difficult circumstances. Proven problem-solving skills while under pressure while upholding observance to a company's rules and regulations.

Efficient time management driven individual who excels at the prospect of a challenge. Experience in creating web pages and applying Javascript/JQuery programing to make the website or app functional.

### **Highlights**

Bilingual: English and Spanish Eight (8) Years Customer Service Efficient on Ten Key Excellent De-escalation Skills Efficient Time Management Strong Communicative Skills Quick Study Strong Work Ethic Extremely Flexible Organized

#### Skills

HTML CSS JavaScript JQuery

## **Projects**

**Weather App:** Upon entering a city name, the current weather information will display. This includes temperature, humidity, UV index, and wind speed. It also provides a 5 day forecast. The languages used include HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery.

URL: https://scottdouglas238.github.io/Weather\_App/

**Hops and Hounds:** The user enters in their zip code and is taken to a page that displays the local breweries in their area. Not only this, but these breweries specifically have outdoor seating equipped for the avid dog lover. This app also displays the current weather, as well the weather information for the next 3 days.

URL: Coming soon.

**Day Calendar:** Data is input by the user in different time slots. Clicking the save button on the right of each slot will save the information in Local Storage. The color of the time slots changes depending of the time of day, representing if the slots are in the past, present, or future.

URL: https://scottdouglas238.github.io/Homework-Calender/

## **Accomplishments**

Class rank was 8 out of 295 Gave the commencement speech at the graduating ceremony.

## **Experience**

#### Programmer

I have worked by myself and with teams towards building functional apps and websites. I am currently studying at the University of Arizona acquiring new skills and learning to master HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery. I have experience using third party APIs while building several applications using the data provided said APIs.

Customer Experience Representative GM Financial (<u>August 2016 – Present - Chandler, AZ</u>) - First line of defense for the overall customer experience. Responsible for solving complex financial issues while demonstrating compliance to legal requirements through multi-channel requests. Close adherence to company policy while processing payment transactions, accurately documenting the system of record, providing customers with correct information, and adhering to the permitted stipulations as outlined under the Fair Credit Report Act (FCRA). Exhibit expert knowledge on title handling which comprises of out of state registration, paid off accounts, title corrections, repo titles and lien perfections. Was part of the team that led the implementation of a more advanced client-oriented interface. Assisted in the training and development of new representatives by demonstrating effective communication skills as well as expertise in all aspects of the position. Demonstrated extraordinary flexibility by accomplishing related duties, projects, and assignments as requested. Moved laterally within the company to the following position:

**Service Specialist – GM Financial** (*July 2018 – July 2019 Chandler, AZ*) – Primarily responsible for de-escalating situations in which customers required the attention of a supervisor. Displayed calm under pressure in high stress situations that required additional research and time necessary to fulfill customers' needs. Calculated excel documents in order to verify the accuracy of a customer's payment history by creating custom mathematical formulas compatible with the system interface. Successfully followed up with customers to create the goal of retaining customers for life. Was given the task to ensure other agent's compliance by approving due date changes, deferred payments, allocation requests, and title releases. Participated in meetings which focused on streamlining the customer experience. Led my piers in this position to overcome obstacles through encouragement, assistance with account maintenance, and proving a foremost exemplar.

**Customer Service Representative - Select Blinds** (11/2015 to 05/2016 Mesa, AZ) - I assisted customers and directed them toward products that would best fit their needs. This included processing orders/sales, educating customers about specific products, and communicating with our manufacturers in regard to specific instructions from the customers. I learned how to multi-task complex tasks with an emphasis on prioritization. Effective time management was key to success in the company, as well as a diligent work ethic. My attention to detail was well received and celebrated during my employment.

**Roofer Quality First Roofing** (05/2015 to 09/2015 Show Low, AZ) - Responsibility of a given job to ensure a roof was "watertight," and up to par with the company standards of "Quality First." I worked on many different styles of roof including shingle, tile, Duralast, and metal. Towards the end of my employment with Quality First, I became a job leader and led my crew successfully in completing given tasks. Had to use strong communications methods to ensure worker's compliance in effectively completing a job.

Bank Teller - FirstBank (12/2013 to 04/2015 Scottsdale, AZ) - Daily duties included processing cash withdrawals, adhering to FirstBank's security and audit procedures, researching and resolving customer issues on personal savings, checking, lines of credit accounts, examining checks for identification and endorsement (many being of high volume), and delivering prompt, accurate and excellent customer service. I was also the collections leading operative, which comprised of calling, and mailing letters to customers with overdrawn accounts in order to contribute to the company's objectives aimed at lowering customer delinquency.

# **Education**

**High School Diploma**: **High School** Pinnacle Education Mesa Community College Scottsdale Community College

The University of Arizona: Computer Coding Boot Camp Program